# Jack Baker

↑ 24 Kelsey Street, Lancaster, LA15DL

 $\square$  jackbaker92@mail.com  $\square$  +447989901918

• https://github.com/jbaker92/

https://lancs.ac.uk/~bakerj1/

Data scientist educated to PhD level in computational statistics and machine learning. Experience developing machine learning models in Python, R and TensorFlow. Relevant internships which required working with SQL, Hadoop architecture and Python data science tools.

## **Technical Summary**

**Expert:** statistics, machine learning, Python, R.

**Proficient:** TensorFlow, unix/shell, version control (git), scikit-learn.

Familiar: SQL, Hadoop, C, NLTK.

## Experience

#### Travelling in Australia

Jan 2019 – Apr 2019

### PhD Student, Lancaster University & University of Washington Oct 2015 – Dec 2018

- PhD student in computational statistics and machine learning at STOR-i, a leading centre for doctoral training in statistics in the UK. PhD in collaboration with University of Washington.
- Submitted thesis consists of three (first author) publications accepted to leading journals in machine learning, computational statistics and statistical software (see overleaf).
- Worked on training Bayesian models at large scale. Developed complex models in Python/R; e.g. recommender systems, Bayesian neural networks, and Dirichlet processes (see GitHub).
- Developed an R package in TensorFlow: sgmcmc (see publications).
- Tutored data science & statistics students at Lancaster University and Edinburgh University.

#### Data Science Intern, Improve Digital

July 2016 - Oct 2016

- Analysed customer advertising data to support data tech team.
- Included topic modelling, classification, forecasting and simulation modelling in Python.
- Data stored in a Hadoop architecture, accessed using Python, SQL and ibis.
- Analysis enabled tech team to roll out a new feature with confidence in performance.

### Data Science Intern, Met Office

Jun 2013 – Aug 2013

- Analysed the performance and usage of the 100TB per day MASS storage system.
- Developed a web interface for visualisation of key metrics. Used by the climate IT team.

#### Development Intern, Motorola Solutions

Jul 2011 – Aug 2011

• Developed an efficient compression algorithm in C for the data on Motorola's wireless products.

## Other Professional Experience

Contributor: Data science tutorials at Cambridge Spark (2018, see website).

Invited Speaker: University of Warwick (2018); University of Edinburgh (2017).

Invited Reviewer: Leading conferences on AI/Machine learning: NIPS (2018); UAI (2018).

Awarded Grants: Extended research visit to University of Washington (2017); expenses for industrial data science consulting week, Alan Turing Institute (2016); travel to present at international Bayesian conference, Switzerland (2016).

Chair: Talks and tutorials on tech for the STOR-i institute (2015–2018, see website).

IP Market Research: Voluntary project for 4 months, University Enterprise Centre (2016).

Outreach Lead: Various impact sessions for schools (2018, see website).

Contributed Speaker: Numerous statistics conferences (2015–2018, see website).

Keen Runner: run two marathons, a mountain marathon, and numerous races (2008–2018)

### Education

PhD, Computational Statistics & Machine Learning Lancaster University & University of Washington Full scholarship and stipend. STOR-i Centre for Doctoral Training.	Oct 2015 – Dec 2018
MRes, Statistics and Operational Research. Distinction (81%) Lancaster University Full scholarship and stipend. STOR-i Centre for Doctoral Training.	Oct 2014 – Sep 2015
BSc, Mathematics and Statistics. First Class Honours (83%) Edinburgh University	Sep 2010 – July 2014

### **Publications**

- § J. Baker, P. Fearnhead, E. B. Fox and C. Nemeth (2018), Large-Scale Stochastic Sampling from the Probability Simplex. Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems 31.
- § J. Baker, P. Fearnhead, E. B. Fox and C. Nemeth (2018), Control Variates for Stochastic Gradient MCMC. Statistics and Computing.
- § J. Baker, P. Fearnhead, E. B. Fox and C. Nemeth (2017), sgmcmc: An R Package for Stochastic Gradient Markov Chain Monte Carlo. Journal of Statistical Software (to appear).